Guide to the John Hope Franklin papers, 1891-2010, bulk 1950-2010 RL.10029
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings By Others (WO), 1940s-2000s; 23 boxes
  - Grimes-Robinson, Kyra M. (Box WO10)
  - Grover, Kathryn (Box WO10)
  - Groves, Harry E. (Box WO10)
  - Guilford, James E. (Jr.) (Box WO10)
  - Gutman, Herb G. (Box WO10)
  - Haines, Corrie (Box WO10)
  - Hall, Kermit (Box WO10)
  - Hall, Paula M. Q. (Box WO10)
  - Ham, Debra M. (Box WO10)
  - Hamilton, Charles V. (Box WO10)
  - Hamilton, Edith (Box WO10)
  - Hamlin, Deborah (Box WO10)
  - Hamlin, Deborah (Box WO23)
  - Hardeman, Martin J. (Box WO10)
  - Hargrove, Jesse J. (Box WO10)
  - Harlan, Louis R. (Box WO10)
  - Harlan, Malvina S. (Box WO10)
  - Harley, Sharon (Box WO10)
  - Harper, Jennifer (Box WO10)
  - Harris, Abram L. (Box WO10)
  - Hart, Charles D. (Box WO10)
  - Haskell, Harry G. (Jr.) (Box WO10)
  - Hawkins, Hunt (Box WO10)
  - Hayes, Lawrence J. W. (Box WO10)
  - Haynes, Titus (Box WO10)
  - Hayward, Emma R. (Box WO10)
  - Hazard, Geoffrey C. (Box WO10)
  - Hendrick, George (Box WO10)
  - Herrup, Cynthia D. (Box WO10)
  - Hertzberg, Stephen (Box WO10)
  - Higgenbothan, Evelyn B., 3 folders (Box WO11)
  - Higginbotham, A. Leon (Box WO11)
  - Higginson, John (Box WO11)
  - Hildebrand, Reginald (Box WO11)
  - Hill, Herbert (Box WO11)
  - Hill, Lemuel L. (Box WO11)
  - Hill, Lynda A., 2 folders (Box WO11)
  - Hine, Darlene C. (Box WO11)
  - Holden, Matthew (Jr.) (Box WO11)
  - Hollifield, Dona (Box WO11)
  - Holt, Thomas C. (Box WO11)
  - Horton, James O. (Box WO11)
  - Hossfeld, Leslie, 2 folders (Box WO11)
  - Howard, Richard (Box WO11)
  - Hoy, Suellen (Box WO11)
  - Hucles, Michael (Box WO11)
  - Huggins, Nathan I. (Box WO11)
  - Humphreys, Lloyd G. (Box WO11)
  - Hurwitz, Samuel J. (Box WO11)
  - Husen, Torsten (Box WO11)
  - Hyman, Harold M. (Box WO11)
  - Isaacs, Harold R. (Box WO11)
  - Jackson, Jesse L. (Jr.), 2 folders (Box WO11)
  - Jackson, Luther P. (Jr.) (Box WO11)
  - Jackson, Phillip (Box WO11)
  - Jackson, Walter A. (Box WO11)
  - Jacobs, Samuel D. (Box WO11)
  - Jaffe, Harry (Box WO11)
  - Jaher, Frederic C. (Box WO11)
  - James, D. Clayton, 3 folders (Box WO12)
  - James, Sherman A. (Box WO12)
  - Janken, Kenneth R. (Box WO12)
  - Jarrett, Thomas D. (Box WO12)
  - Jefferson, Alphine W. (Box WO12)
  - Jemison, Marie S. (Box WO12)
  - Jerome, V. J. (Box WO12)
  - Johnson, Charles D. (Box WO12)
  - Johnson, Hannibal (Box WO12)
  - Johnson, Jerah (Box WO12)
  - Johnson, Lyman M. (Box WO12)
  - Johnson, Walter (Box WO12)
  - Johnston, Edward (Box WO12)
  - Johnston, Harry (Box WO12)
  - Johnston, James H. (Box WO12)
  - Jones, Louis C. (Box WO12)
  - Jones, Maxine E. (Box WO12)
  - Jones, Howard M. (Box WO12)
  - Jones, Waldo E. (II) (Box WO12)
  - Jordan, Alphonzo (Box WO12)
  - Jordan, Ervin L. (Box WO12)
  - Jordan, Winthrop (Box WO12)
  - Kalra, Paul (Box WO12)
  - Kammen, Michael G. (Box WO12)
  - Kaplan, Sidney (Box WO12)
  - Karl, Barry D. (Box WO12)
  - Katz, Friedrich (Box WO12)
  - Katz, Stanley N. (Box WO12)
  - Keillor, Garrison (Box WO12)
  - Keita, S. O. Y. (Box WO12)
  - Keith, John W. (Jr.) (Box WO12)
  - Keithley, Rod (Box WO12)
  - Keller, Frances R. (Box WO12)
  - Kennedy, Joseph A. (Box WO12)
  - Kennedy, Randall (Box WO12)
  - Kennedy, Roger G., 2 folders (Box WO12)
  - Kenzer, Robert C. (Box WO13)
  - Kerber, Linda K. (Box WO13)
  - Kerr, W. G. (Box WO13)
  - Kersten, Andrew E. (Box WO13)
  - Kilson, Martin (Box WO13)
  - Kincaid, Larry (Box WO13)
  - King, Martin Luther (Jr.) (Box WO13)
  - Klarman, Michael J. (Box WO13)
  - Klein, Milton M. (Box WO13)
  - Knight, Arthur (Box WO13)
  - Koegnisberger, Dorothy (Box WO13)
  - Kofsky, Frank (Box WO13)
  - Kohrman, Daniel B. (Box WO13)
  - Kolchin, Peter (Box WO13)
  - Kong, B. Waine (Box WO13)
  - Kozol, Jonathan (Box WO13)
  - Krause, Allen (Box WO13)
  - Krenn, Michael L. (Box WO13)
  - Krieger, Leonard (Box WO13)
  - Kousser, J. Morgan (Box WO13)
  - Kusmer, Kenneth L. (Box WO13)
  - Kyvig, David E. (Box WO13)
  - Lakoff, Sanford A. (Box WO13)
  - Laney, Garrine P., 2 folders (Box WO13)
  - Lauren, Paul G. (Box WO13)
  - Laves, Walter H. C. (Box WO13)
  - Lawrence, Frederick M. (Box WO13)
  - Lawrence, Jacob (Box WO13)
  - Lawson, Steven F. (Box WO13)
  - LeDuc, Thomas (Box WO13)
  - Leiter, William M., 2 folders (Box WO13)
  - Leuchtenburg, William E., 2 folders (Box WO13)
  - Levi, Edward H. (Box WO14)
  - Levine, Lawrence W. (Box WO14)
  - Lewis, David L. (Box WO14)
  - Lewis, Harold O. (Box WO14)
  - Lewis, James W. (Box WO14)
  - Linder, Mark (Box WO14)
  - Lindsay, Beverly, 7 folders (Box WO14)
  - Link, Arthur S. (Box WO14)
  - Lofton, Williston H. (Box WO14)
  - Logan, Frenise A. (Box WO14)
  - Logan, Rayford W. (Box WO14)
  - Long, Charles H. (Box WO14)
  - [Louise, E.] (Box WO14)
  - Loury, Glenn C. (Box WO14)
  - Love, Spencie (Box WO14)
  - Low, W. A. (Box WO14)
  - Lutze, Karl E. (Box WO14)
  - Mack, Kenneth W. (Box WO14)
  - Madgett, Naomi L. (Box WO14)
  - Malone, Rick, 2 folders (Box WO14)
  - Maltz, Earl (Box WO14)
  - Manasse, Ernst M. (Box WO14)
  - Manley, A. E. (Box WO14)
  - Mann, Arthur (Box WO14)
  - Manning, Thomas G. (Box WO14)
  - Marable, Manning (ed.) (Box WO14)
  - Marotti, Frank (Jr.) (Box WO15)
  - Martin, Waldo E. (Box WO15)
  - Marty, Martin E. (Box WO15)
  - Mason, Skip, 2 folders (Box WO15)
  - Massa, Ann (Box WO15)
  - Mathews, David (Box WO15)
  - Mathews, Marcia M. (Box WO15)
  - Mathis, Robert N. (Box WO15)
  - May, Ernest R. (Box WO15)
  - Mayer, Henry, 4 folders (Box WO15)
  - Mazel, Ella (Box WO15)
  - McAllister, W. K. (Box WO15)
  - McAnear, Beverly (Box WO15)
  - McConahay, John B. (Box WO15)
  - McConnell, Roland C. (Box WO15)
  - McCraw, Thomas K., 2 folders (Box WO15)
  - McElreath, J. Michael (Box WO15)
  - McGowan, James A. (Box WO15)
  - McGraw, B. T. (Box WO15)
  - McKelvey, Blake (Box WO15)
  - McKenzie, Edna (Box WO15)
  - McMillan, Karen D. (Box WO15)
  - McPherson, James M. (Box WO15)
  - McStallworth, Paul (Box WO15)
  - Meier, August (Box WO15)
  - Merriam, Allen H. (Box WO15)
  - Merrill, Claire (Box WO15)
  - Metcalfe, Ralph (Jr.), 2 folders (Box WO16)
  - Meyer, William S. (Box WO16)
  - Miller, Rhonda (Box WO16)
  - Mohr, Clarence L. (Box WO16)
  - Moore, N. Webster (Jr.) (Box WO16)
  - Morgan, Edmund (Box WO16)
  - Morgan, Gordon D. (Box WO16)
  - Morris, Richard B. (Box WO16)
  - Morris, Thomas D. (Box WO16)
  - Moskos, Charles C. (Box WO16)
  - Moss, Juanita P. (Box WO16)
  - Muirhead, Jack (Box WO16)
  - Mullikin, Kent (Box WO16)
  - Mvusi, Thandekile R. M. (Box WO16)
  - Naidis, Mark (Box WO16)
  - Ndove, Nelson J. (Box WO16)
  - Nelson, America E. (Box WO16)
  - Nerlove, Marc (Box WO16)
  - Neu, Charles, 2 folders (Box WO16)
  - Nevins, Allan (Box WO16)
  - Newell, Alex (Box WO16)
  - Newkirk, Pamela (Box WO16)
  - Niven, John (Box WO16)
  - Norris, Harold (Box WO16)
  - Noyes, Marje (Box WO16)
  - Numbers, Ronald L. (ed.) (Box WO16)
  - Ogletree, Charles J., 3 folders (Box WO16)
  - Oh, Angela E. (Box WO16)
  - Oldham, James (Box WO16)
  - Olsen, Judy W-B. (Box WO16)
  - Orfield, Gary (Box WO16)
  - Osakwe, Loretta (Box WO16)
  - Osthaus, Carl R. (Box WO16)
  - Padilla, Arthur (Box WO17)
  - Painter, Nell I. (Box WO17)
  - Palmer, Paul C. (Box WO17)
  - Palmer, R. R. (Box WO17)
  - Palmer, Ronald D. (Box WO17)
  - Parker, Freddie L. (Box WO17)
  - Parmet, Herbert S. (Box WO17)
  - Patience, Alice P. (Box WO17)
  - Pease, William H. (Box WO17)
  - PeHit, W. T. (Box WO17)
  - Peyre, Henri (Box WO17)
  - Philipson, Morris (Box WO17)
  - Phillips, Maverick (Box WO17)
  - Pinkett, Harold T. (Box WO17)
  - Pole, J. R. (Box WO17)
  - Polenberg, Richard (Box WO17)
  - Pollard, Alton B. (Box WO17)
  - Popkin, Jeremy D. (Box WO17)
  - Porter, Coni (Box WO17)
  - Porter, Dorothy B. (Box WO17)
  - Prather, H. Leon, 4 folders (Box WO17)
  - Pressly, Thomas J. (Box WO17)
  - Quick, Charles W. (Box WO17)
  - Quiros, Luis (Box WO17)
  - Rabinowitz, Howard N. (Box WO17)
  - Randall, Alice (Box WO17)
  - Reddick, L. D. (Box WO17)
  - Reed, Richard C. (Box WO17)
  - Rees, Mina (Box WO17)
  - Reynold, P. Preston, 3 folders (Box WO17)
  - Ricceur, Paul (Box WO18)
  - Riley, Norman (Box WO18)
  - Rivers, Larry E., 4 folders (Box WO18)
  - Roach, Max (Box WO18)
  - Robb, John M. (Box WO18)
  - Rodriguez, Richard (Box WO18)
  - Rogers, Kim L. (Box WO18)
  - Ronnick, Michele V., 3 folders (Box WO18)
  - Roper, Laura W. (Box WO18)
  - Rosen, Louis (Box WO18)
  - Ross, Don (Box WO18)
  - Ross, Rod (Box WO18)
  - Rothhammer, Joshua H. (Box WO18)
  - Rubio, Phillip F., 2 folders (Box WO18)
  - Russell, Thomas D. (Box WO18)
  - Salk, Erwin A. (Box WO18)
  - Salvatore, Nick (Box WO18)
  - Sanders, Crystal (Box WO18)
  - Schaller, Michael, 2 folders (Box WO18)
  - Scheiber, Harry N. (Box WO18)
  - Scheiner, Seth M. (Box WO18)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur (Jr.) (Box WO18)
  - [Schell, James] (Box WO18)
  - Schmid, Carol (Box WO18)
  - Schrock, G. K. (Box WO18)
  - Schwade, John (Box WO19)
  - Schwartz, Harold (Box WO19)
  - Schwartzman, David (Box WO19)
  - Schweninger, Loren (Box WO19)
  - Scott, John A. (Box WO19)
  - Scott, John H. (Box WO19)
  - Scott, Nathan A. (Jr.) (Box WO19)
  - Scott, Wendy B. (Box WO19)
  - Scultz, Theodore W. (Box WO19)
  - Seay, Soloman S. (Jr.) (Box WO19)
  - Secrest, Andrew M. (Box WO19)
  - Sekyi, Henry V. H. (Box WO19)
  - Setton, Kenneth M. (Box WO19)
  - Shapiro, Herbert (Box WO19)
  - Sheeler, J. Reuben (Box WO19)
  - Sheppard, Eric A. (Box WO19)
  - Shepperson, George (Box WO19)
  - Shiner, Michael (Box WO19)
  - Simkins, Francis B. (Box WO19)
  - Simmons, Christina (Box WO19)
  - Singer, Milton (Box WO19)
  - Sinha, Manisha (Box WO19)
  - Slade, Leonard A. (Box WO19)
  - Smallwood, Arwin D. (Box WO19)
  - Smith, David L. (Box WO19)
  - Smith, J. Clay (Jr.) (Box WO19)
  - Smith, Jerome S. (Box WO19)
  - Smith, John D. (Box WO19)
  - Smith, Karen P. (Box WO19)
  - Smith, Robert C. (Box WO19)
  - Snyder, Brad M. (Box WO19)
  - Spady, James G. (Box WO19)
  - Spencer, Samuel R. (Box WO19)
  - Spurlock, Jeanne (Box WO19)
  - Stampp, Kenneth M. (Box WO19)
  - Stanton, Mary (Box WO19)
  - Stauber, Leland G. (Box WO19)
  - St. Clair, Gabrael (Box WO19)
  - Sterling, Richard W. (Box WO19)
  - Stewart, Charles C. (Box WO19)
  - Stewart, M. LeSueur (Box WO19)
  - Storr, Robert (Box WO19)
  - Strecker, John (Box WO19)
  - [Stuckey, P. Sterling] (Box WO19)
  - Sturm, Circe (Box WO19)
  - Sue, Derald W. (Box WO19)
  - Sutton, Ozell (Box WO19)
  - Swanson, James L., 2 folders (Box WO20)
  - Sweat, Edward F. (Box WO20)
  - Sydnor, Charles S. (Box WO20)
  - Taulbert, Clifton L. (Box WO20)
  - Taylor, Philip A. (Box WO20)
  - Taylor, William L. (Box WO20)
  - Tetlow, Tania (Box WO20)
  - Thomas, Lawrence (Box WO20)
  - Thuesen, Sarah C. (Box WO20)
  - Tilly, Louise A. (Box WO20)
  - Townsend, Ronald, 2 folders (Box WO20)
  - Trouillot, Michel-Rolph (Box WO20)
  - Turner, Elizabeth H. (Box WO20)
  - Tyson, Tim (ed.), 3 folders (Box WO20)
  - Urban, Wayne J. (Box WO20)
  - Van Alstyne, William W. (Box WO20)
  - Venerable, Grant (Box WO20)
  - Wade-Lewis, Margaret (Box WO20)
  - Wadelington, Charles W. (Box WO20)
  - Walker, Frank (Box WO20)
  - Walker, Juliet E. K. (Box WO20)
  - Wall, Bennett H. (Box WO20)
  - Wallenstein, Peter (Box WO20)
  - Ward, Geoffrey (Box WO20)
  - Ward, Jason M. (Box WO21)
  - Washburn, Wilcomb (Box WO21)
  - Washington, George L. (Box WO21)
  - Waters, Darin (Box WO21)
  - Weatherford, Allen E. (Box WO21)
  - Weaver, John C. (Box WO21)
  - Webb, Samuel L. (Box WO21)
  - Wharton, Clifton R. (Jr.) (Box WO21)
  - Whitaker, Robert (Box WO21)
  - White, Claytee D. (Box WO21)
  - White, John (Box WO21)
  - White, Joseph L. (Box WO21)
  - Whitten, David O. (Box WO21)
  - Wickett, Murray R. (Box WO21)
  - Wiegand, Wayne A. (Box WO21)
  - Williams, Frank J., 2 folders (Box WO21)
  - Williams, Juan (Box WO21)
  - Williams, Patricia J. (Box WO21)
  - Willis, Holly (Box WO21)
  - Willis, Kimberly (Box WO21)
  - Wilson, Ernest J. (III) (Box WO21)
  - Wilson, William J. (Box WO21)
  - Winborne, Wayne (ed.) (Box WO21)
  - Wood, Peter H. (Box WO21)
  - Woodworth, Steven A., 2 folders (Box WO21)
  - Wright, Edward T. (Box WO21)
  - Wright, Marion T. (Box WO21)
  - Xu-Yi, Lin (Box WO22)
  - Zax, Leonard A. (Box WO22)
  - Zwillenberg, Paul (Box WO22)
  - Authors Unknown, 5 folders (Box WO22)
  - Drafts of writings by others with correspondence to JHF, 1998-2002; 3 folders (Box W43)
    A mix of academic and non-academic writings. Some involve complaints of discrimination, sent by ordinary citizens to John Hope Franklin.
- Courtland Cox Papers (CC), 1963-1970s; 10 folders 1 box
  Series consists of papers collected by Franklin, related to Courtland Cox, civil rights activist, member of the Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee, and supporter of minority business rights. The papers contain some records of Cox's Washington, D.C. business, Drum and Spear Bookstore, writings by Cox, and some correspondence, as well as six folders of publicity and other records of the 6th Pan-African Congress, held in Tanzania in 1973. Cox played a key role in organizing the conference.
  Related Materials
  Courtland Cox papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Duke University (part of the SNCC Legacy project).
  Biographical / Historical
  Excerpted from the SNCC Legacy Project website:
  While a Howard University student, Courtland Cox became a member of NAG and the Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC). He worked with SNCC in Mississippi and Lowndes County, Alabama, was the Program Secretary for SNCC in 1962, and was the SNCC representative to the War Crimes Tribunal organized by Bertrand Russell. In 1963 he served as the SNCC representative on the Steering Committee for the March on Washington. In 1973 Mr. Cox served as the Secretary General of the Sixth Pan-African Congress and international meeting of African people in Tanzania. He co-owned and managed the Drum and Spear bookstore and Drum and Spear Press. Cox is presently a Consultant with the D.C. Public Schools. Cox was appointed by President Clinton to serve as the Director of the Minority Business Development Agency (MBDA) at the Department of Commerce, a position he held until January 20, 2001.
  - Printed material and correspondence, 1963-1974 (Box CC1)
  - FOIA requests, FBI files, 1969-1972 (Box CC1)
  - Drum and Spear Bookstore, financial and other records, 1970s (Box CC1)
  - Pan-African Congress, Tanzania, 1972-1974; 6 folders (Box CC1)
    Contains a rich assemblage of meeting minutes, planning notes; conference agendas; lists of participants; calls for action; platforms on issues such as apartheid, French colonialism, and black power; reports during and after the Congress; photocopied clippings; and articles by Cox on the conference.
  - Writings by Courtland Cox, 1970s (Box CC1)
    Contains various writings: partial interview script, with "Mimi," Cox, and Charlie Cobb, on black liberation and other topics; various writings on black power, apartheid, and minority economic justice; and a bibliography on works about insurgencies, guerilla warfare, and non-conventional war.